CV (curriculum vitae)



Resume

Cand.it with 4 years of student work experience with marketing at the web agency Webstarters. My studies have contributed to competencies like research, analyzing, and assessment of user experience in terms of methods and an agile mindset. Fieldwork can contribute to a company's understanding of its users and the users' experience with the company. My student job has likewise made me able to work within an organizational context outside the academic field, where time, customers, and productivity are highly prioritized.

The competencies I have achieved at my bachelor and master are among others user studies, evaluation of UI in regards to UX and usability, IT-Didactic within organizations, interaction design, system development in regards to agile development, Project Management, programming, organization communication, value-based design, Web communication, and narratives within and around organizations.

As a person, I am very creative and hardworking. Most people would describe me as a positive and engaged person, who works well in a group environment. My professional and personal competencies can contribute to this job opportunity and your company in general.

Work Experience

Freelance, Taskflex

oct. 2019 - mar. 2019 - Student job

In the last quarter of 2019, I had my own customer. I helped her with Facebook Marketing, which involved Business Manager setup, campaign structure, ad structure, product catalog and ad creation. The first month resulted in a ROI of 17.08, 48 purchases and 131 new relevant leads.

SoMe-Specialist, Webstarters

jan. 2019 - jul. 2019 - Student job

I always wanted to learn as much as possible during my time at university. Webstarters has been a great company for that. I tried different branches within online marketing. The latest branch was Facebook Paid Marketing.

SEO Account Manager, Webstarters

mar. 2017 - jan. 2019 - Student job

I was responsible for SEO and writing linkbuilding content. My job was to help our customers reach great results in the search engine, Google. I worked with both Off-page SEO, On-page SEO and linkbuilding.

Freelance Content Writer, Webstarters

apr. 2016 - mar. 2017 - Student job

I started working as a freelance content writer for Webstarters and other companies. Webstarters hired me as their employee after working for one year as a freelance writer.

Cashier / Key holder, Super Brugsen

2010 - 2015 - - Student job

Jeg arbejdede 5 år I Super Brugsen imens jeg var i folkeskole og gymnasiet. Jeg arbejdede i grøntafdelingen, hjalp kunder, sad i kassen og de sidste 2 år arbejdede jeg som lukkeansvarlig. Jeg stod derfor for at lukke butikken, som består af 100+ ansatte.

Education

Master's Degree - Webcommunication Design, SDU Kolding

2018 - 2020

Bachelor's Degree - Information Technology, IT, and Interaction Design, SDU Kolding 2015 – 2018

Programming

- HTML and CSS
- JavaScript
- Agile development principles
- Basic understanding of Git (Version control)
- Github: https://github.com/brandtiboy
- Portfolio: https://www.frederikbrandt.dk/
- UX Case Study: Language Learning Case Study

Besides my education I have studied programming to develop my skills further in this department. I document my journey on my Instagram account (<u>Take a look</u>).

Language

Danish

First language

English

Proficient

Personal

In my spare time, I enjoy playing competitive video games. I always loved being competitive and therefore I also played a lot of soccer up until gymnasium. I played in Parken (Danish national soccer stadium) in a School soccer tournament and I won firmaCS (Company Counter-strike tournament) with Webstarters back in 2018.

I also enjoy being creative with painting, video editing, and such. Other than that, I enjoy being active, being with friends and family, and to have a good time. Besides that, I read books like The Lean Startup and Hacking Growth: How Today's Fastest-Growing Companies Drive Breakout Success to advance my knowledge.

Academic projects

Bachelor Project

My bachelor project was about Esport education at a school. Here we analyzed the current educational foundation, where we collected video data about the education and made interviews, where both of them were analyzed. This became the foundation for developing a design proposal, which should improve the current teaching. We managed to develop a minimal viable product in the shape of a website and a short video, which was a low-fidelity prototype. Today several businesses have used these findings.

Master Thesis

On the 2nd of June 2020 we submitted our master thesis. The delimitation for the master thesis was generation z. We wanted to investigate there use of the internet and how the gaming- and streaming industries have adopted to that behavior and used it to their advantage. The theoretical foundation revolved around disruption and innovation, which many industries experience. Spotify disrupted the music industry and Netflix disrupted the way we watch movies and TV series. Through our analysis of the gaming- and streaming industries, which both have success with generation z, we established five tendencies. These five tendencies were tested on two companies in a Business Model Canvas, where we attempted to use these tendencies and think creatively. One of the companies was a music festival. The tendencies suggested an online festival. Three weeks after our analysis another music festival announced an online festival. Our master thesis has, therefore to some degree, predicted the future and could have helped the music festival to avoid suffering under a potential disruption within their industry.

Creative projects I made

- I have built a blog for 7 years ago, where we made YouTube videos with upcoming influencers. It's in
 Danish and it now has around 44.000 views (<u>Look here</u>).
- I made a podcast with my study buddy and produced it myself. Also in Danish (<u>Listen here</u>).
- Before COVID-19 I built a travel blog in WordPress and wrote comprehensive blog posts, which is fully SEO optimized. In Danish (Read my London Post).
- During the past 10 years I have edited videos as a hobby. Some of my videos are upload on my Danish YouTube Channel (Watch here).
- I will update my portfolio with projects I have built from scratch. That is everything from a conversion app to a UX case study (<u>Link to my portfolio</u>).

Publications

"5 gode råd til dig der vil i gang med din første webshop". Billy.dk 9. november 2017 Guest Blog post for the company, Billy's Billing, which is one of the largest economy programs in Denmark. It is written in Danish.

https://www.billy.dk/blog/5-gode-raad-til-dig-der-vil-i-gang-med-din-foerste-webshop/